<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Zoë Haime</title>
    <link>https://zoehaime.com/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://zoehaime.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://zoehaime.com/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>ECHR Conference 2019 - Durham</title>
      <link>https://zoehaime.com/post/blog1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://zoehaime.com/post/blog1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ECHR Conference 2019!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to write a quick blog about my first experience presenting at a conference and how I feel about it now on reflection. I was lucky enough to have my abstract accepted for the 2nd annual ECHR conference in Durham, UK. Not only was this the first conference I would be attending alone, it was also the first one I&#39;d been to outside London, and the first one I would be presenting at - nervewracking!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://zoehaime.com/post/blog1/index_files/ECHR.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;echrlogo&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my job I&#39;m used to travelling across the UK, so getting on a train to Durham wasn&#39;t a huge deal, despite it taking a good few hours to get that far North!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As this was a conference of firsts for me, I thought I&#39;d go through some of my main pros/cons below:
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Pros&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Getting to do my first conference presentation to an audience that &lt;strong&gt;mainly&lt;/strong&gt; consisted of early career researchers was far less intimidating than expected. Everyone was interested, and the questions were less scary than I predicted. All in all it boosted my confidence ten-fold.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got to meet the programme manager for a similar study to the one I work on, that&#39;s running in The Netherlands. From this introduction we are now co-organising a workshop, so the networking element was a huge positive for me!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The location and facilities were great, I was able to stay in a cheap hotel a short walk away, and on my way back to the train station I made sure to take a look at the beautiful cathedral and town centre.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The presentations were all in a similar field of cognition to myself, and were organised really well. I found even the topics I&#39;m less aware of were interesting to me. I think overall the content of the day was provocative and inspiring.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;m a part-time PhD student, and that meant I had to get back to London to work the day after my presentation. This meant I left the conference just after lunchtime, which was hugely disappointing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Going it alone is terrifying. I always see people tweet about knowing just one person at a conference and sticking with them. I knew no-one! This is again a con of being a part-time student, I&#39;m never around the university department meeting people (and can never make the scheduled PhD student meetings). I felt quite welcomed at this conference, and a few people made a real effort to approach me. At a more senior conference though I&#39;m not sure I would have felt as at ease.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I felt even more &amp;lsquo;early&amp;rsquo; than the other early career researchers. I had just started looking at my systematic review results whilst some people were nearing the end of their PhD. It made me feel like a bit of a fraud, with the classic imposter syndrome never too far away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meeting other researchers who are full-time made me all the more aware of the resources they have, that I&#39;m missing. Although I have a very supportive department and team, they seem to have unlimited access to peer support, career opportunities, and supervisor contact. Also how are they all affording to go to multiple conferences internationally? This was my only conference of the year.
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
My presentation focused on my systematic review findings, you can see my aims slide below.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://zoehaime.com/post/blog1/index_files/ECHR_pres.png&#34; alt=&#34;ECHRpres1&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://zoehaime.com/post/blog1/index_files/ECHR_pres2.png&#34; alt=&#34;ECHRpres2&#34;&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I will soon write a blog on my systematic review process and results. Below I have included an example of the morning programme from this conference in case others are interested in attending a future meeting. I would highly recommend going and using the opportunity to present your work if you&#39;re in the early stages of your PhD or research career.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://zoehaime.com/post/blog1/index_files/ECHRprogramme.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;ECHRprog&#34;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;did-you-find-this-page-interesting-consider-sharing-it-&#34;&gt;Did you find this page interesting? Consider sharing it 🙌&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing Your Upgrade Exam During a Worldwide Pandemic</title>
      <link>https://zoehaime.com/post/blog2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://zoehaime.com/post/blog2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;did-you-find-this-page-interesting-consider-sharing-it-&#34;&gt;Did you find this page interesting? Consider sharing it 🙌&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
