<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Communication | Zoë Haime</title>
    <link>https://zoehaime.com/categories/communication/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://zoehaime.com/categories/communication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Communication</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Communication</title>
      <link>https://zoehaime.com/categories/communication/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing Your Upgrade Exam During a Worldwide Pandemic</title>
      <link>https://zoehaime.com/post/blog4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://zoehaime.com/post/blog4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;did-you-find-this-page-interesting-consider-sharing-it-&#34;&gt;Did you find this page interesting? Consider sharing it 🙌&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Engagement and Science Communication</title>
      <link>https://zoehaime.com/post/blog3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://zoehaime.com/post/blog3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As an Early Career Researcher (ECR) I feel like I have been lucky to live in an era where twitter exists. I have gained so much knowledge and advice from the platform, and I have been able to stay up-to-date with the latest research developments in my area. That&#39;s not to say it isn&#39;t overwhelming though, every couple of minutes there&#39;s a new deluge of information, chat, and criticism on my timeline, and this has made it difficult to sort the wheat from the chaff sometimes, or even worse, made it impossible to stop working!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I can really see the benefits in making science more accessible through social media. When I was younger I don&#39;t know how I would have learnt more about my future career. I didn&#39;t know anyone in academia (no-one before my brother went to university in our family), I didn&#39;t live near a university (the closest one would have been 1.5hrs away), and even if I searched the internet I wouldn&#39;t have known what to look for! That&#39;s why I&#39;ve been really excited to recently take part in a science engagement initiative called &amp;lsquo;I&#39;m a Scientist, Stay At Home&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The premise of the activity is a website with different scientific areas (I&#39;m part of the psychology zone), where scientists create a fun and interesting profile about themselves. Teachers or group leaders can then sign-up their students to take part in asking questions to the scientists, be involved in live chats, and every week vote for their favourite scientist. The website encourages students to ask questions not only about current scientific endeavours, but about scientists career paths, or even just their personalities. The aim is to encourage children into STEM careers, but also to make science accessible and understandable to a wider, and younger audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have had great fun taking part in the live chats with the children. Most of those interested in the psychology zone have been sixth form students looking for an honest insight into studying psychology at university, and the career outlook from there. They have also asked some really thoughtful and intelligent questions about my speciifc research, which has allowed me to practice talking about my work in an accessible way, and filled me with excitement that younger people are interested in such a critical area of study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week is loneliness awareness week and I will be taking part in some extra chats to discuss the topic of loneliness with other psychology researchers, and the children. I think it is great that during this Covid-19 time, this outlet exists, for both the scientists and the young people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am really hoping to continue improving my science communication during my PhD, but I have found this to be a really great first step in helping me get across my research in a simple and understandable way, whilst also hopefully creating interest in the subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;did-you-find-this-page-interesting-consider-sharing-it-&#34;&gt;Did you find this page interesting? Consider sharing it 🙌&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
